BPX batch is provided to make it easier to run shell scripts in ZOS UNIX application programs that reside in HFS through the ZOS batch environment.
Users that do most of their work in TSOE can use BPX batch instead of entering the shell.
BPX batch can be invoked by JCL as a batch job, as a command in TSOE, from within a rex exec or with oshell.
ZOS UNIX C programs require the standard in, standard out and standard error be defined.
Many C functions also use this to define input and output.
For BPX batch, the default for standard in and standard out is slash dev slash null, and standard error is the same as standard out.
This can be changed to far names by using the dd names stdin, stdout and stderr.
Limitations in BPX batch input and output make it more difficult to create and maintain BPX batch jobs compared to other batch utilities.
But BPX batch has been enhanced to allow far greater parameter input and to allow output to be directed to traditional ZOS datasets.
BPX batch allows up to 64k of parameter data to be supplied as input to BPX batch.
It also allows both standard out and standard error to specify additional ZOS datasets to be the target of the output of the BPX batch jobs.
BPX batch supports up to, and let's be more precise than 64k here, it supports 65,536 characters parameter data.
This is supported by using a standard palm dd that points to a ZOS dataset or Unix file that contains the parameter data.
The ZOS datasets that can be used include sysin, sequential and pds, pdse members.
BPX batch now also supports the specification of ZOS datasets on the standard out and standard error dd's.
This allows output from BPX batch jobs to be directed to sysout datasets, sequential datasets, or pdse members.
To avoid truncation of the output lines, the lraquel of one or more datasets should be large enough to handle lines of output from typical Unix commands.
Here's an example of a BPX batch job.
Notice BPX batch allows both standard out and standard error to specify traditional ZOS datasets to be the target of the output of the BPX batch jobs.
BPX batsl provides you with an alternative entry point into BPX batch and forces a program to run using a local spawn instead of fork or exec, as BPX batch does.
This ultimately allows a program to run faster.
Here we see BPX batsl running a local spawn of programs.
In the next video, we're going to look at solutions to address some common problems.